I am what we got one the point that was
made by a number of this linkage to
justice and rights because I think it is
probably one of the most important
building blocks on which we need to
concentrate in the coming years justice
is something that we can interpret as
intrinsic as being part of their society
of a social contract but now silently
the transactions also at least the right
of recourse through our courts to the
justice system through the judiciary I
just want to draw your attention to
Congress that he invited to here
together with the president Harper's
including the Supreme Court or state
tribunal i think it is called of the
state of a visionary behind Chief
Justice's attorneys general prosecutor's
general and auditors general
conference here this week to discuss
with them the relationship between the
sustainable development agenda energy
judicial process and it is a fascinating
today because if you want to talk about
rights it is not just a matter of the
territory this course it is also than
accepting that you have a right to
recall your right to seek justice you
have a right to look at somewhere in
your society for an authority that could
ensure that these rights out help and
it's a fascinating discussion because
the responses Congress overwhelmed us oh
no got 100 of them came because the
sustainability the environment conflicts
in the leakage in social and
environmental rights is pushing through
the front doors of course all across the
world including here preserve as well
Indian and many development projects end
up in the course in India it like
interesting phenomenon of a society
trying to find the resolution
irreconcilable interest
way I think we need to focus a lot more
on the traditional system or the
judiciary alongside the executive and
the legislative and this is also calling
for the intergenerational contract
because one of the great races are the
democracies that it plays the interests
of the majority and in an
intergenerational context it doesn't
take much marginal imagination who is
going to win the present against the
future and I think is important that the
courts become part of the system
protecting the rights of those who are
not in bonilla and this is particularly
true when it comes to sustainability
sustainable development environment on
the comment about global citizen
movement absolutely I think we we also
saw in Rio a certain disarray in the
global social movements and there are
movements with very particular realities
the realities of South America of
indigenous peoples here of the land
rights movement these are very immediate
very direct very alive problems
occupations which I've met many people
have a disengagement from the political
system in defense or lots of trust and
faith these are not problems of let's
say civil society in other parts world
maybe Asia or Europe or the United
States or even Africa I think secondly
they also have a moment where the global
citizens movement is in search of an
agenda that can also bind together is
very different realities and you know
for me it is not a matter of finding one
conversation it would be a madness to
search that in our diverse world but I
think we see a lot of critique here but
I think soul Society also has ability to
put many more alternatives forward it is
not a lack of capacity to stab the lack
of a coherent conversation if you want
and one of the last speakers prefer just
now to other creative parts of our
society of skill say that they have the
comment you know there are some who were
under the covers are not subject to the
tragedy as defined or the failure of
governance and rights but it is an eye
for all you know in the tradition of
Elena
a Nobel Prize economist fine how the
comments a manageable but she said it oh
yes you can choose different models but
for God's I can only do something about
it because the way you're doing it right
now you dig nothing and if you simply
critique and you haven't evolved a
social and economic model on how to make
it work then we'll continue discussing
it fine point wine we go on those
plastic bubbles you know I think this is
where I believe in so many of the
examples that you know input in this
report all the transition towards a
green economy because at the end of the
day you can blame this morning's
organizers to have a key focus here but
you know if you open anything like this
are you going to worry about anybody
here or you going to worry about where
the drinks are going to come from this
is what we also need to put the kind of
incentives and regulatory system in
place that either you have tracks of
water in all public venues as being a
normality or you have maybe a level that
make sure that bottles are recycled
we have a very interesting moment I was
all the ninety-eight percent of all
drinks containers maybe I mean
containers are recycled why did that
happen well because there was some
legislation for a place there are some
economic incentives people collect these
things and they recycle them okay you
may say let's not happen in the first
place but you know we don't always eat
in place where we have a type of water
so we do need containers the phones
they're interesting example 100 million
cell phones are now sold every year the
world market 1 billion now how do you
eating with the recycling is this
extraordinary amount of material that
gets thrown away lies and drawers or
lands of the landfills of the world a
comp like Africa they're also part of an
e-waste problem now the problem is the
technology to recycle in cell phones is
actually very sophisticated media
decoupling transfer company so instead
of talking you should be making sure
that every African nation for example
has
sighs OH SAT phones and recuperate all
these precious metals record mistakes
instead of letting them be put on the
waist Alps of our planet what I'm trying
to get to is the enhanced as a comic in
address this issue from the past
important to the cell phone to renewable
energy and i want to say because i often
feel as if you know there is a reception
that media nominations don't do things
in the way that we talk about we try and
i'm not very interesting example in 30
seconds what you have to do you going
before accommodating the unit because we
have to move on with the owner and I
Romy the question was what we're going
to just know another building like it
has always known or would we build
something that speaks to the you know
the mission of which is cleaner energy
less wise etc if you then went into the
United Nations regulations on how you
could do this you would have given up
because it's also the fundamental
premise of public for human a budget in
the UN is you build a building and then
it's done to try and come with
energy in this case a photovoltaic
infrastructure that you would have to
pay eight years of electricity bill to
advance in order 15-20 years when a free
electricity afterwards was
irreconcilable with a budget system of
the United Nations and the same is true
for virtually every heavily so we have
to change color procurement they have to
change the locals in our society that
help citizens to not make the
alternative of the plastic bottle ten
times what it should be taken one to use
public transport moving around vo in the
21st century is also a failure urban
planning and this is a city that is
suffocate loads on traffic but it's
actually impossibility to solve now we
know how this work done but it is the
new urban development concepts they need
to be implemented my part is we can get
active on the Class C bollywood go three
steps were the bank and ask yourself
hardly make it easier more viable and
also accessible for citizens to do the
right thing the more intelligent think
the less destructive thing because they
live up to it nobody wants to have
plastic bubble if they have an alternate
that's better doesn't cost more and it's
actually something that they have access
to this is I think what you have to
begin to learn the lessons that we have
learned every country think it's time to
me but you just come to me because they
don't go back to the fundamental root
and keep all the symptoms on the focus
so just a few responses to the questions
and as I particular one that emphasizes
the global citizens movement is vital
it's fundamentally but our voice I can
assure you nothing will really change
because the systems are there are good
in the Crescent thank